<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>https://brains4bots.site/</id><title>Brains 4 Bots</title><subtitle>A short collection of interactive and engaging problems, which aim to teach Python and Programmer mindset.</subtitle> <updated>2021-08-11T17:06:19+10:00</updated> <author> <name>Jackson Goerner</name> <uri>https://brains4bots.site/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://brains4bots.site/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" href="https://brains4bots.site/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2021 Jackson Goerner </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>Setup</title><link href="https://brains4bots.site/posts/setup/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Setup" /><published>2021-01-01T12:00:00+11:00</published> <updated>2021-06-17T11:27:11+10:00</updated> <id>https://brains4bots.site/posts/setup/</id> <content src="https://brains4bots.site/posts/setup/" /> <author> <name>Jackson Goerner</name> </author> <summary> In this page we’ll do all the setup necessary to write and run Python programs in EV3Sim on our computers. It shouldn’t take too long, and you’ll run your first Python program by the end of it! Why VSCode? All python programs are written in plain old text, just like a bunch of other documents on your computer, so why do we need a special program to write Python code? The main reas... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Loops and Infrared</title><link href="https://brains4bots.site/posts/repeat/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Loops and Infrared" /><published>2021-01-01T12:00:00+11:00</published> <updated>2021-07-04T20:10:07+10:00</updated> <id>https://brains4bots.site/posts/repeat/</id> <content src="https://brains4bots.site/posts/repeat/" /> <author> <name>Jackson Goerner</name> </author> <summary> Now it’s starting to get interesting, and our robots are taking shape. This workshop we’ll start following a ball (or alien?), and introduce the next tool in our toolbox - The while loop! We’ll finish by hunting some aliens, and counting how many different coloured ones we see: What are they and why do we need them? While conditionals have allowed us to make code that r... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Lists and Compass</title><link href="https://brains4bots.site/posts/lists/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lists and Compass" /><published>2021-01-01T12:00:00+11:00</published> <updated>2021-07-26T11:13:42+10:00</updated> <id>https://brains4bots.site/posts/lists/</id> <content src="https://brains4bots.site/posts/lists/" /> <author> <name>Jackson Goerner</name> </author> <summary> As we further expand our toolbox for programming, we’ll look at how we can store a bunch of variables at once, and use that alongside a compass sensor! Why lists? At this point, hopefully you agree that we can do a lot of cool and different things with our programs. In the last post, we learnt how to make code repeat certain instructions for an arbitrarily long time (Repeat t... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Basics of Python</title><link href="https://brains4bots.site/posts/intro/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Basics of Python" /><published>2021-01-01T12:00:00+11:00</published> <updated>2021-07-25T13:13:30+10:00</updated> <id>https://brains4bots.site/posts/intro/</id> <content src="https://brains4bots.site/posts/intro/" /> <author> <name>Jackson Goerner</name> </author> <summary> By the end of this page, you’ll understand the very basics of how Python works, and we’ll use that to make a robot move on our command, to reach a flag! Recap / What is Python? As we were setting up Python last time, we ran some sample code and just checked that everything worked (If it didn’t, make sure to go back through the previous page). Today let’s try to explain what... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Sensors and Conditionals</title><link href="https://brains4bots.site/posts/if-else/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sensors and Conditionals" /><published>2021-01-01T12:00:00+11:00</published> <updated>2021-07-27T11:13:24+10:00</updated> <id>https://brains4bots.site/posts/if-else/</id> <content src="https://brains4bots.site/posts/if-else/" /> <author> <name>Jackson Goerner</name> </author> <summary> By the end of this page, you will understand how code can make decisions, and use this to create a robot that can expertly work its way out of a maze, using sensors! So far in our coding puzzles, our programs have really only been able to do a single task, such as move to a point or print some information. Reusing our previous recipe analogy, recipes might give different inst... </summary> </entry> </feed>
